<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Code Chronicle</title>
    <link>https://medalhas.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Code Chronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 20:17:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://medalhas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Medalhas&#39;s Curated Collection</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 20:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share with you my curated collection of bookmarks with articles and videos that have caught my attention and fueled my curiosity.&#xA;Within thix page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a diverse range of content spanning various topics, from technology, leadership and productivity. Each link represents a doorway to a world of knowledge, offering insights, perspectives, and discoveries that have resonated with me on a personal and professional level.&#xA;Guys that I follow Scott Hanselman Blog Simon Sinek - Youtube channel Theo - Youtube channel Nick Chapsas - Youtube channel about C# The PrimeTimeagen - Youtube channel about tech Documentaries Node.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 22:07:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description>About me Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Luis Medalhas. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in software engineering for more than 20 years. Throughout my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked from small companies to large corporations, each of them contributing to my growth.&#xA;For 4 years, I had the opportunity to work as an engineering lead, a position that allowed me to mix my passion for managing people with my love for technical challenges. While I thrived in leading teams, I tried for staying connected with the technical stuff of the projects, ensuring that I remain hands-on with the development process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>📈 Monitoring a Camel application with Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/monitoring-spring-camel-apps-with-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 18:36:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/monitoring-spring-camel-apps-with-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Why monitoring? In software engineering monitoring plays an important role in fault detection, performance improvements, the health of an application, resource planning, and based on the previous continuous improvements of the application. Having an application in a live environment it&amp;rsquo;s important to have observability to understand how our application behaves and also for a quick response.&#xA;How can we do it? We have several ways and tools at our disposal that we can use to monitor an application:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🗣 The gentle art of giving feedback!</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 22:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description>What is feedback and why is important? Feedback, by definition, is information given to someone about their performance or behavior to help them to improve and thrive in the future.&#xA;Positive feedback vs Negative feedback Commonly we use the terms positive feedback or negative feedback, I don&amp;rsquo;t love those terms, good feedback can&amp;rsquo;t be negative.&#xA;I prefer to split them by the objective, so we have:&#xA;Growth feedback Praise feedback Growth feedback They have different objectives, the first one is to help the subject to improve and grow in their career, it&amp;rsquo;s fundamental for a manager to give growth feedback.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🏠 Thoughts About Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</guid>
      <description>Summary The Covid-19 vírus force us to make some changes in our lives, one of them it’s to stay safe at home and favor the remote work.&#xA;This is a subject that caught my attention recently as I work daily with people spread across remote locations and us as a team had to adapt.&#xA;Working remotely has many advantages, like the time we save in commuting, optimize the focus time as we can fewer interruptions, more environment-friendly, people can be better distributed across the countries and not so concentrated in big urban areas and other many more that I just can’t remember.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
