<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed_style.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="https://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">
  <channel>
    <title>Medalhas&#39;s memory dump</title>
    <link>https://medalhas.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Medalhas&#39;s memory dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 22:28:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medalhas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><icon>https://medalhas.github.io/img/icon.svg</icon>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The gentle art of giving feedback!</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 22:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-feedback-and-why-is-important">What is feedback and why is important?</h2>
<p>Feedback, by definition, is information given to someone about their performance or behavior to help them to improve and thrive in the future.</p>
<h2 id="positive-feedback-vs-negative-feedback">Positive feedback vs Negative feedback</h2>
<p>Commonly we use the terms positive feedback or negative feedback, I don&rsquo;t love those terms, good feedback can&rsquo;t be negative.</p>
<p>I prefer to split them by the objective, so we have:</p>
<ul>
<li>Growth feedback</li>
<li>Praise feedback</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="growth-feedback">Growth feedback</h3>
<p>They have different objectives, the first one is to help the subject to improve and grow in their career, it&rsquo;s fundamental for a manager to give growth feedback.
One common mistake is to confuse feedback with a reprimand, this is important to maintain the focus on the objective of the feedback, as it has the goal for the other party to listen, understand and take actions to improve the performance or the behavior, so the communication must be clear, with the right tone and the right message.</p>
<h4 id="tone-of-voice">Tone of Voice</h4>
<p>Your tone of voice expresses your emotions or feelings and encompasses not only the words you choose but also the way deliver them.
The way you speak a message is as important as the message itself. It means that you can convey different meanings or emotions based on the tone of your voice, even if you use the same words.  Therefore, when delivering a message, paying attention to both the words and the tone you use is essential to ensure that your message is received as intended.</p>
<p>Even if the message itself is well-crafted, if it is delivered in an aggressive tone, the receiver will most likely react defensively, and the intended meaning may be lost.
The amygdala, the part of the brain responsible for processing emotions, will be the first to respond to a message delivered in an aggressive tone. However, to ensure that the intended message is understood, it is crucial to communicate with the prefrontal cortex, the part of the brain responsible for rational thinking.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the way you deliver a message is just as crucial as the message itself, and it is important to keep in mind that the tone in which you deliver the message can either facilitate or hinder effective communication. By being mindful of your tone of voice, you can improve your ability to give feedback effectively to others.</p>
<h4 id="how-to-build-your-message">How to build your message?</h4>
<p>The Situation-Behavior-Impact (SBI) framework is a simple and effective way to give feedback. It consists of three parts:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Situation</strong>: Explain the context where the behavior occurred, this helps to set the stage for the feedback and helps the receiver to understand the specific situation where the behavior was observed.</li>
<li><strong>Behavior</strong>: Explain the observed behavior, be objective and limited to facts, and keep out opinions or judgments.</li>
<li><strong>Impact</strong>: This is the effect or consequence of the behavior, explain how the behavior impacted others or the situation.</li>
</ol>
<p>Using this framework will help you to deliver very specific, objective, and constructive feedback that helps the receiver understand the impact of their behavior and how to improve it.</p>
<h3 id="praise-feedback">Praise feedback</h3>
<p>Forgotten by some managers and overused by others, praise feedback has the goal to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Motivate</li>
<li>Build confidence</li>
<li>Encourage the good behavior</li>
</ul>
<p>With that being said those three factors will increase the productivity of an individual or the team, they&rsquo;ll feel that their work/behavior was appreciated and awareness that they are on the right path and will be more confident to take more risks and encourage them to repeat the good behavior.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve started this section by saying that some managers overused it, and this can be dangerous and counterproductive in the long term.
When praise feedback is given too often or without meaningful substance, it can lead to a culture of complacency, where individuals expect to be praised for the most basic tasks. And in the long term can lead to a decrease in motivation and effort, as individuals may feel that their efforts are already being recognized and appreciated, and therefore they may not see the need to strive for better performance.</p>
<p>When giving praise feedback we can use the same Situation-Behavior-Impact (SBI) framework described previously. Don&rsquo;t just say &ldquo;good job&rdquo;, be specific about the situation and behavior and explain the positive impact.</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts About Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>The Covid-19 vírus force us to make some changes in our lives, one of them it’s to stay safe at home and favor the remote work.</p>
<p>This is a subject that caught my attention recently as I work daily with people spread across remote locations and us as a team had to adapt.</p>
<p>Working remotely has many advantages, like the time we save in commuting, optimize the focus time as we can fewer interruptions, more environment-friendly, people can be better distributed across the countries and not so concentrated in big urban areas and other many more that I just can’t remember.</p>
<p>I must advise you that I am not a fan of remote work as I miss the contact with the team, but I see it as inevitable in the future.</p>
<p>But it also has many challenges, the lack of social interaction with teammates could lead to a less sense of belonging and affect the teamwork, the home has too many distractions and it demands great discipline, communication also can be challenging as it sometimes it’s just easier to talk or draw a picture.</p>
<p>Some actions can help you face these challenges:</p>
<ul>
<li>Have a dedicated and appropriate space to work;</li>
<li>Create a routine as you’re going to the office, set a wake-up hour, take a bath and dress up, so that you have a work mindset;</li>
<li>Set hours to start and stop working;</li>
<li>Try to go to the cafe or take lunch with a friend, socialize with others.</li>
<li>Make sure you have access to all the tools you need to perform your work (VPN or cloud)</li>
<li>Choose the proper tools for communicating and collaborate with your teammates (BlueJeans, Slack, Zoom, Miro).</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to have your home office well defined, it should be a quiet space without distractions. This is important for you to achieve the focus and take advantage of working at home and be free of office distractions.</p>
<p>Communication with your teammates should be clear so be aware to use proper tools, like a headset with a microphone, be sure to mute your mic when your teammates are talking. It’s important to have your camera on to be more engaged with the team.</p>
<p>The set a schedule it’s also an essential issue as it force you to have a discipline to time to start but also, and not less important, to have time to stop as we don’t want to burnout.</p>
<h2 id="stay-at-home-with-kids">Stay at home with kids</h2>
<p>At this time the challenges are even bigger because we should avoid contact with other people and because schools are closed I have to stay at home with the kids.</p>
<p>In my case, an 11-year-old girl and 5-year-old boy, so at this point taking care of kids and work, looks like two incompatible ideas. I’m in a mix of kind of worried and kind of curious and challenged how it’s going to work.</p>
<p>So I’ve started to I’ve explained to them that although I’m at home I’m working and we worked together in an agreement when they can interrupt me. I have the luck that my kids are very mature for their age but they’re kids anyway.</p>
<p>I will see how it goes…</p>
<h2 id="some-tools-that-can-help-you">Some tools that can help you</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://slack.com/">Slack</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bluejeans.com/">BlueJeans</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.zoom.us/">Zoom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://miro.com/">Miro</a></li>
<li><a href="https://funretro.io/">FunRetro</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>My name is <strong>Luís Medalhas</strong> and Engineer Lead on <a href="https://www.farfetch.com/">Farfetch</a> and a career since 1998. This site is a tool to express some thoughts about several subjects that I care.
To write is a way to structure my thougths and investigate, some of them reflect personal experience.</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
