<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Code Chronicle</title>
    <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Code Chronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 18:36:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://medalhas.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>📈 Monitoring a Camel application with Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/monitoring-spring-camel-apps-with-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 18:36:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/monitoring-spring-camel-apps-with-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Why monitoring? In software engineering monitoring plays an important role in fault detection, performance improvements, the health of an application, resource planning, and based on the previous continuous improvements of the application. Having an application in a live environment it&amp;rsquo;s important to have observability to understand how our application behaves and also for a quick response.&#xA;How can we do it? We have several ways and tools at our disposal that we can use to monitor an application:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🗣 The gentle art of giving feedback!</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 22:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/the-gentle-art-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description>What is feedback and why is important? Feedback, by definition, is information given to someone about their performance or behavior to help them to improve and thrive in the future.&#xA;Positive feedback vs Negative feedback Commonly we use the terms positive feedback or negative feedback, I don&amp;rsquo;t love those terms, good feedback can&amp;rsquo;t be negative.&#xA;I prefer to split them by the objective, so we have:&#xA;Growth feedback Praise feedback Growth feedback They have different objectives, the first one is to help the subject to improve and grow in their career, it&amp;rsquo;s fundamental for a manager to give growth feedback.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🏠 Thoughts About Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medalhas.github.io/posts/thoughts-about-remote-work/</guid>
      <description>Summary The Covid-19 vírus force us to make some changes in our lives, one of them it’s to stay safe at home and favor the remote work.&#xA;This is a subject that caught my attention recently as I work daily with people spread across remote locations and us as a team had to adapt.&#xA;Working remotely has many advantages, like the time we save in commuting, optimize the focus time as we can fewer interruptions, more environment-friendly, people can be better distributed across the countries and not so concentrated in big urban areas and other many more that I just can’t remember.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
